神秘博士第一季第一集
洛斯
我走了 -再见
Bye. - See you later.
顾客朋友请注意
This is a customer announcement.
本店将于五分钟后结束营业 多谢惠顾
The store closes in five minutes. Thank you.
威尔森
Wilson?
威尔森 彩金在我这里
Wilson, I've got the lottery money.
威尔森
Wilson?
你在里面吗
You there?
我等不了多久 店门就要锁了
I can't hang about cos they're closing the shop.
威尔森
Wilson?
哪去了
Come on...
谁在那
Hello?
威尔森 我是洛斯
Hello? Wilson, it's Rose.
在吗
Hello?
威尔森
Wilson?
Wilson!
威尔森
Wilson?
是谁在这里装神弄鬼呢
Is that someone mucking about?
到底是谁
Who is it?
好吧 你吓着我了 闹够了
Ok. You got me. Very funny.
你们已经吓到我了
Right, I've got the joke!
这谁出的鬼主意
Whose idea was this?
是德里克的主意吗
Is it Derek's?
是不是
Is it?
德里克 是你搞的鬼吗
Derek, is this you?
跑
Run!
你把他的胳膊扯下来了 -对啊
You pulled his arm off! - Yep.
塑料的
Plastic.
很聪明的恶作剧
Very clever, nice trick.
他们是谁 学生吗 这是学生搞的鬼吗
Who are they, students? Is this a student thing or what?
为什么会是学生
Why would they be students?
我怎么知道
I don't know!
你自己说的 为什么是学生
You said it. Why students?
因为能让这么多人乔装打扮
Cos... to get that many people dressed up
装神弄鬼 也只有学生干得出来了
and being silly hanny, they got to be students.
有道理 说得好
That makes sense. Well done.
多谢
Thanks.
他们不是学生
They're not students.
不管是谁 只要被威尔森抓到就扭送警察
Whoever they are, when Wilson finds them, he'll call the police.
威尔森是谁
Who's Wilson?
他是电工长
Chief electrician.
威尔森已经死了
Wilson's dead.
这不好笑 太过分了
That's just not funny. That's sick!
等下 小心眼睛
Hold on. Mind your eyes.
我真受够你了
I've had enough of this.
你又是谁 楼下那帮到底是谁
Who are you, then? Who's that lot down there...?
我问你呢 他们是谁
I said who are they?
他们是塑料做的 是活的塑料人
They're made of plastic, living plastic creatures.
他们受楼顶上的一个中继装置控制
They're being controlled by a relay device from the roof,
那可是个大麻烦
which would be a great big problem
幸好我有这个
if I didn't have this.
所以我要冲到楼上把它炸了
So I'm gonna go upstairs, and blow it up.
我没准会死掉 不过别担心我
I might well die in the process, but don't worry about me.
你快走 走吧
You go on, go on.
回家去吃你美味的晚餐吧
Go and have your lovely beens on toast.
别向任何人提起这件事
Don't tell anyone about this.
如果你说了 你会把别人害死的
Cos if you do, you'll get them killed.
顺便说下我是博士 你叫什么
I'm the Doctor by the way, what's your name?
洛斯
Rose.
幸会 洛斯 逃命去吧
Nice to meet you, Rose. run for your life!
[百货商店遭遇爆炸事故]
整个伦敦中区均被封锁
The whole of Central London has been closed off
警方正在调查起火原因
as police investigatie the fire.
据此前报道
Early report in the...
我知道 都上电视了 到处都在报道
I know, it's on the telly! it's everywhere!
她命大躲过一劫
She's lucky to be alive!
不过让她老了不少 皮肤皱得跟古籍似的
Honestly, it's aged her. skin like an old Bible.
你要是现在看 你会以为她是我妈
You walking in now you'd think I was her daughter.
啊他来了
Oh, and here's himself.
我一直在打你的手机
I've been phoning your moblie!
你差点就没命了
You could have been dead!
新闻上满天飞
It's on the news and everything!
我不敢相信你的店烧起来了
I can't believe your shop went up!
我没事 真的没事 别大惊小怪的
I'm alright, honestly, I'm fine. Don't make a fuss!
但是怎么回事啊
But what happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
什么原因 怎么烧起来的
What was it then? What caused it?
我又没在店里
I wasn't in the shop.
我当时在外面 什么都没看见
I was outside, I didn't see anything...
黛比打电话来了
It's Debbie on the end.
她认识《每日镜报》的人 五百英镑采访你
She knows a man on the mirror, 500 quid for an interview.
太好了 快给我
Oh, that's brilliant, give it here.
你总得想个路子挣钱吧
You've got to find some way to make money.
你工作泡汤了 我才不会养着你
Your job's kaput and I'm not bailing you out!
贝芙 她还活着
Bev, she's alive!
我告诉她了 打官司索赔
I've told her, sue for compensation...
她差点就死了
She was within seconds of death.
你怎么还喝茶呢
Why are you drinking tea?
不不 这不行这不行 你吓着了
Nah nah, that's not good, that's not good. You're in shock.
你得喝点带劲的 -我没事
You need something stronger. - I'm alright.
来吧 你得好好喝一杯
Now come on. You deserve a proper drink.
咱们这就去酒吧 就咱俩 我出钱买单
we're going down the pub, you and me, my treat, I'll buy.
今天是不是有比赛啊
Is there a match on?
没 没 我关心你呢 宝贝
No, no... I'm just think about you, babe.
就是有比赛 对不对
There's a match on, ain't there?
这不是重点 不过我们能赶上最后五分钟
Well that's not the point. We could catch the last five minutes.
那你就去吧 我真的没事 去吧
Go on, then. I'm fine, really, go.
把那玩意儿扔了
And get rid of that.
再见了 -回见
Bye-bye. - Bye!
有15名消防队员在现场扑救
15 fire crews are attendence
不过据称想保住大楼
though it's thought there's very little chance
已经不太可能
of saving the infrastructure.
你起这么早干嘛 宝贝女儿
There's no point in getting up,sweetheart.
你又没有工作
You've got no job to go to.
你还可以去芬奇家店里试试
There's Finch's. You could try them.
他们一直在招人 -真是好主意 那帮屠夫
They've always got jobs. - Oh, great, the butcher's.
没准对你有好处 那商店惯得你挑三拣四的
It might do you good. That shop you is giving you airs and graces.
我说索赔可没在开玩笑
I'm not joking about compensation,
你可是真的吓出精神创伤了
you've had genuine shock and trauma!
阿里安娜拿到了两千镑
Arianna got 2,000 quid off the council,
就因为办事员说她像希腊人
just cos the old man behind the desk said she looked Greek!
她确实是希腊人 但这不是重点
I know she is Greek, but that's not the point.
你这可是合理索赔
It's a fairly claim.
妈你个大骗子
Mum, you're such a liar!
我告诉你把猫洞钉死
I tole you to nail that cat-flap down.
不然野猫野狗都进来了
Now we're gonna get strays!
我几周前就钉死了
I did it weeks back.
才怪 你以为你钉了
No... you thought about it.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我住这
I live here.
你住这做什么
What would you do that for?
我家在这啊
Cos I do.
我闲在家是因为有人把我工作炸没了
I'm only home cos someone blew up my job!
肯定是信号出问题了 你不是塑料做的吧
I must have the wrong signal. you're not plastic, are you?
不是 榆木脑袋 回见
No, bonehead, bye then.
你给我进来
You, inside, right now.
谁啊
Who is it?
是来说昨晚的事的 他是来调查的
It's about last night. He's part of the inquiry.
给我们十分钟
Give us ten minutes.
她应该得到赔偿
She deserves compensation!
得赔好几百万呢
Oh, we're talking millions.
我…我穿着睡衣呢
I'm... I'm in my dressing gown.
是的 没错
Yes, you are.
我的卧室里有个陌生男人
There's a strange man in my bedroom.
对 没错
Yes, there is. ..
任何事情都有可能发生呢
Well, anything could happen.
不会
No.
一团乱你别介意 想喝咖啡吗
Don't mind the mess. Would you want a coffee?
来一杯也好 多谢 牛奶就行
Might as well, thanks, just milk.
我们应该去找警察
We should go to the police.
说真的 咱俩一起去
Seriously. Both of us.
他们不会长久的 一个是同性恋一个是外星人
That won't last. he's gay and she's an alien.
我倒不是怪你 就算这事真是
I'm not blaming you, even if it was
过了火的恶作剧
some sort of jokes that just went wrong.
悲剧了
Sad ending.
新闻上说他们发现了一具尸体
It said on the news they found a body.
洛斯·泰勒
"Rose Tyler."
还没这么糟嘛 看看这对耳朵
Ah, could've been worse. Look at the ears!
他说还不错 炸得好 -当女人真好
He was saying it was nice. It was a nice bomb. - Luck be a lady.
如果我们要去警察局的话
Anyway, if we are gonna go to the police,
我要知道我该说什么
I wanna know what I'm saying.
我要你解释一切 -也许不会
I want you to explain everyting. - Maybe not.
那是什么
What's that?
你养猫了吗
Have you got a cat?
没啊
No.
以前有 现在只有野猫 从别人家跑来的
We did have, but we just get strays. They come in off the estate.
我让米奇把它扔出去的
I told Mickey to chuck that out.
你们都一个德性 给你们个塑料手就知道开玩笑
You're all the same. Give a man a plastic hand...
我还不知道你叫什么呢 什么博士来着
Anyway, I don't even know your name. Doctor, what was it?
没事了 我让它停下来了
It's all right, I've stopped it.
你看 没杀伤力了 -你真这么想吗
There you go. See, armless. - You think?!
等等 你总不能就这么走了吧
Hold on a minute, you can't just go swanning off?
当然可以了 我正走着呢
Yes I can. Here I am.
这就是我 正在离开 拜拜
This is me, swanning off. See ya!
但那只胳膊在动 它要杀我
But that arm was moving, it tried to kill me!
观察力满分
Ten out of ten for observation.
你不能一走了之 这不公平
You can't just walk away! That's not fair.
你得告诉我怎么回事 -我不会的
You've got to tell me what's going on. - No, I don't.
好吧 那我就去警察局 告诉所有人
All right, then I'll go to the police. I'll tell everyone.
你说如果我说出去 会害死别人
You said, if I did that, I'd get people killed.
你自己选吧 告诉我或者我说出去
So, your choice. Tell me or I'll start talking.
你是在威胁我吗
Is that supposed to sound tough?
差不多吧
Sort of.
没用
Doesn't work.
你是谁
Who are you?
告诉过你了 博士
Told you, the Doctor.
对 但是 什么博士
Yeah, but doctor what?
就叫博士
Just the Doctor.
博士吗 -你好啊
The Doctor? - Hello!
我应该觉得久仰大名吗
Is that supposed to sound impressive?
差不多
Sort of.
拜托 告诉我吧 我都看见了
Come on then, you can tell me. I've seen enough.
你是警察吗
Are you the police?
不是 只是当时路过而已
No! I was just passing through.
我离家有点远
I'm a long way from home...
但是我做错了什么
But what have I done wrong?
为什么那些塑料人一直追我呢
How come those plastic things keep coming after me?
好像突然全世界都绕着你转了似的
Oh, suddenly the entire world revolves around you.
你是个意外 只是挡道了而已
You were just an accident. You got in the way, that's all.
它可是要杀我啊
It tried to kill me!
它在追的是我 不是你
It was after me, not you!
昨夜我在店里 你忽然跑进来
Last night in the shop, I was there, you blundered in,
差点毁了我的计划
almost ruined the whole thing!
今天早上我在追踪它 它也在追踪我
This morning, I was tracking it down, it was tracking me down.
它盯着你不放是因为你碰见我了
It fixed on you 'cos you'd met me.
你是说全世界都绕着你转吗
So, you're saying is the entire world revolves around you?
差不多是的
Sort of, yeah.
你真是个自大狂
You're full of it!
差不多吧 是的
Sort of, yeah.
还有谁知道这些塑料家伙的事 -没别人
All this plastic stuff, who else knows about it? - No one.
你只有一个人吗
What, you're on your own?
那还有谁一起呢
Well, who else is there?
你们这些人只会
I mean, you lot, all you do is
吃薯片 爬上床 看电视
eat chips, go on bed, and watch Tele.
而在你们身旁一场战争正如火如荼
While all the time underneath you there's a war going on.
好吧 从头开始说
Ok. Start from the beginning.
如果我们要对付活的塑料人
I mean, if we're going with living plastic,
虽然我其实并不相信这个
and I don't even believe that.
如果不得已 你怎么干掉它
If we do, how did you kill it?
控制者将生命投射进塑料手臂里
The thing controlling it projects life into the arm.
我切断了信号 它就完蛋了
I cut off the signal. Dead.
是用电波控制吗 -思维控制
So that's radio control? - Thought control.
你没事吧 -没事
You're all right? - Yeah.
那控制者是谁
So... who's controlling it, then?
说来话长 -这都是为了什么呢
Long story. - What's it all for?
橱窗里的塑料模特 能干什么
I mean, shop window dummies, what's that about?
有人要控制全英国的商店吗
Someone trying to take over Britain's shops.
不是
No!
好吧 不是 -这不是价格战争
Well, no! - It's not a price war.
它们想要侵略地球 毁灭人类
They want to overthrow the human race and destroy you.
你相信吗 -不信
Do you believe me? - No.
但你仍然在听
But you're still listening.
说真的 博士 告诉我
Really, though, Doctor... tell me.
你是谁
Who are you?
就像我们刚才说的
Do you know like we were saying,
关于地球转动的事情
about the Earth revolving?
比如你小时候
It's like when you're a kid,
当人们第一次告诉你世界在转动时
the first time they tell you the world's turning
你不敢相信
and you just can't quite believe it
因为一切看上去都是静止的
cos it looks like everything's standing still.
而我能感觉得到
I can feel it.
地球的转动
The turn of the Earth.
我们脚下的土地
The ground beneath our feet
在以每小时1600公里的速度旋转
is spinning at 1000 miles an hour.
整个星球绕着太阳旋转
The entire planet is hurtling round the sun
每小时飞驰11万公里
at 67000 miles an hour.
我能感觉到 我们在空间中穿梭 你和我
I can feel it, we're falling through space, you and me.
紧紧依附于这个小小世界的表面
Clinging to the skin of this tiny little world,
但如果我们放开手
and if we let go...
这就是我 现在忘了我吧 洛斯·泰勒
That's who I am. Now forget me, Rose Tyler.
回家吧
Go home.
我的宝贝回来啦 正好 -闭嘴吧你
Hey hey, here's my woman! Kit off. - Oh shut up.
来点咖啡吗 -好啊 只要你洗杯子
Coffee? - Yeah, only if you wash the mug.
我不是说冲一冲 而是好好洗
I don't mean rinse, I mean wash.
我能用你的电脑吗
Can I use your computer?
行 想用什么理由进我卧室都行
Yeah, any excuse to get in the bedroom.
别看我的邮件
Don't read my e-mails!
博士
博士 活的塑料人
博士 蓝盒子
博士是谁
博士是谁 你见过这个人吗
博士是谁 你见过这个人吗 请联系克莱夫
你见过这个人吗 请联系克莱夫
你不用进来
You're not coming in.
他很安全的 有妻有子
He's safe, he's got a wife and kids.
是谁告诉你的 是他
Who told you that? He did!
网络上的杀人狂就会这么说
That's exactly what an Internet lunatic murderer would say!
你好 我是来找克莱夫的 我们电邮联系过的
Um, hello, I've come to see Clive. We've been e-mailing.
爸爸 又来了一个疯子
Dad! It's one of your nutters.
抱歉 你好 你一定是洛斯吧
Sorry. Hello! You must be Rose.
我是克莱夫 显然
I'm Clive. obviously.
我最好提前说一下 我男朋友在车里等我
I'd better tell you now - my boyfriend's waiting in the car,
他怕你把我杀了
in case you kill me.
不会的 他担心得对 这里没有杀人犯
No, good point! No murders!
是谁
Who is it?
是关于博士的 她浏览了我的网站
It's somethign to do with the Doctor, she's been reading the website.
请进 我在工具间里
Please come through, I'm in the shed.
"她" 她浏览了关于博士的网站吗
She? She's read a website about the Doctor?
真的是"她"吗
She's a she?
这个话题有很多敏感内容
A lot of this is quite sensitive,
我不能随便发出去
I couldn't just send it yet.
可能会有人拦截 你明白的
People might intercept. If you know what I mean.
如果你挖得足够深
If you dig deep enough
保持开放思维
and keep a lively mind,
会发现这个博士在各个地方出没
this Doctor keeps cropping up all over the place.
政治日记 阴谋论 甚至是鬼故事里
Political diaries, conspiracy theories, even ghost stories.
无名无姓
No first name, no last name,
只是叫博士 总是叫博士
just the Doctor, always the Doctor.
这个称号好像代代流传
The title seems to be passed down from father to son,
像是继承的称呼
and it appears to be an inheritance.
你见到的博士长这样 是吗
That's your Doctor there, isn't it?
对
Yeah.
我直到去年才追查到
Yeah. I tracked it down to the Washington Public Archive,
华盛顿公共档案馆
just last year.
网上的照片被增强过了
The online photo's enhanced,
但如果我们看看原始照片
but if we look at the original...
1963年11月22日
November 22nd 1963,
肯尼迪总统遇刺
the assassination of President Kennedy.
一定是他父亲吧
Must be his father.
再往前追溯
Going further back...
1912年4月
April 1912.
这是南安普顿
This is a photograph of
丹尼尔一家与朋友的照片
the Daniels family of Southampton, and friend.
是在他们出发去新大陆的前一天拍摄的
This was taken the day before they were due to go to the new world,
乘坐泰坦尼克号
on the Titanic.
但不知为什么
But for some unknown reason,
他们取消了行程 逃过一劫
they cancelled the trip and survived.
这一张
And here we are...
1883年 又一个博士
1883, another Doctor.
看 完全相同的血统 长得一模一样
Look, the same lineage, he's identical...
这个人在喀拉喀托火山爆发当晚
This one washed up on the Sumatran coast,
被冲上了苏门答腊岛的海岸
the very night Krakatoa exploded.
博士就是一个传说 贯穿于历史之中
The Doctor is a legend, woven throughout history.
哪里有灾难 哪里就有他
When disaster comes, he's there.
他一出现就会带来风暴
He brings the storm in his wake,
他还有一个固定的同伴
and has one constant companion.
那是谁
Who is that?
死神
Death.
如果博士又回来了 如果你见到他 洛斯
If the Doctor's back, if you've seen him, Rose,
那么有一点可以确定
then one thing's for certain.
我们有危险了
We're all in danger.
给我出来
Come on then.
如果他选择了你
If he singled you out,
如果博士找上了你
if the Doctor's making house calls...
你只能自求多福
then God help you.
可他究竟是谁
But who is he?
你觉得他究竟是谁
Who do you think he is?
我觉得都是同一个人
I think he's the same man.
我认为他是长生不老的
I think he's immortal.
我认为他是来自另一个世界的外星人
I think he's an alien from another world.
好吧 他是个疯子 神经兮兮的
All right, he's a nutter. Off his head.
是个彻头彻尾的阴谋家 你赢了
Complete online conspiracy freak, you win!
我们今晚有什么安排
So, what are we going to do tonight?
我想吃披萨
I fancy a pizza.
披萨
Pizza!
披萨 -中国菜也行
Pizza! - Or Chinese.
披萨
Pizzaaaaaaaa!
我应该去医院试试吗
Should I try the hospital?
苏琪说他们的餐厅缺人
Suki said they had jobs going in the canteen.
所以我得去发薯片了吗
Is that it then, dishing out chips?
我也可以去考大学 我不知道
I could do A-Levels. I dunno.
都怪吉米·斯通斯
It's all Jimmy Stones's fault.
都是他害我上不成学 再看看他的结果
I only left school cus of him and look where he ended up.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
你在哪儿遇到这个博士的
So where did you meet this Doctor?
抱歉 我是在说我的事
Oh, sorry, was I talking about me?
我想应该是在那家商店 对吗
I reckon it started at the shop, am I right?
他和爆炸有关吗 -没有
Was he something to do with that? - No.
别这样
Come on.
有点吧
Sort of.
他在那儿做什么
What was he doing there?
我不想说这个 米奇 真的不想说
I'm not going on about it, really, Mickey, I'm not.
我知道这听起来很傻
Cos I know it sounds daft,
可我觉得和他在一起不安全
but I don't think he's safe.
他很危险 -你要相信我 宝贝
He's dangerous. - You can trust me, sweetheart.
宝贝 亲爱的 甜心
Babe, darling, sugar...
你什么都可以跟我说 告诉我博士的事
You can tell me anything. Tell me about the Doctor
以及他的计划 我可以帮你 洛斯
and what he's planning and I can help you, Rose.
我就是想帮帮你而已 宝贝
That's what I want to do, sweetheart,
亲爱的 宝贝 甜心
darling, babe, sugar, sweetheart.
你怎么了 -您的香槟
What are you doing that for? - Your champagne.
我们没点香槟
We didn't order any.
博士在哪儿 -小姐 您的香槟
Where's the Doctor? - Madam, your champagne.
不是我们点的 米奇 怎么了
It's not ours. Mickey, what is it, what's wrong?
我要知道他究竟知道多少 他在哪儿
I need know out how much he knows, so where is he?
没有人要这瓶香槟吗
Doesn't anybody want this champagne?
听着 我们没点…
Look, we didn't order...
找到你了
Ah, gotcha.
别管我 我只是要为二位祝酒呢
Don't mind me. I'm just toasting the happy couple.
免费赠送
On the house!
好了
Anyway!
不要以为这样就能阻止我
Don't think that's gonna stop me.
所有人立刻离开这里
Everyone, out, now!
快出去 快出去 快出去
Get out, get out, get out!
用你那个小玩意儿把门打开
Open the gate! use that tube thing!
这是音速起子 -快用啊
Sonic screwdriver. - Use it!
不 听我的 到里面去
Nah, tell you what, let's go in here.
藏在个木箱子里管什么用
I can't hide in a wooden box!
他会抓到我们的
He's gonna get us!
博士
Doctor!
它会跟上来的
It's gonna follow us.
连成吉思汗的铁骑
The assembled hordes of Genghis Khan
都闯不进这扇门
couldn't get through that door.
相信我 他们真的试过 现在你安静一会
Believe me, they've tried! now, shut up a minute.
它们的胳膊构造太简单
You see, the arm was too simple,
脑袋则正合适
but a head's perfect.
我可以用它跟踪这个信号
I can use it to trace the signal
找到信号的来源
back to the original source.
好了 你想从什么问起
Right. Where would you want to start?
这个盒子里面比外面还要大吗
Um... the inside's bigger than the outside.
没错 -是外星科技吧
Yes. - It's... alien.
是的
Yep...
你是外星人吗
Are you alien?
是的
Yes.
你还好吗 -还好
Is that all right? - Yeah.
这个盒子叫做塔迪斯
It's called the TARDIS, this thing.
是时间和空间相对维度的简称
T-A-R-D-I-S, that's time and relative dimension in space.
没关系 文化冲击
That's ok. Culture shock.
这种情况经常发生
Happens to the best of us.
它们杀了米奇吗
Did they kill him? Mickey?
它们杀了米奇吗 他死了吗
Did they kill Mickey? Is he dead?
我没想到这个问题
Oh, I didn't think of that.
他是我的男朋友
He's my boyfriend!
你拧下了他的脑袋
You pulled off his head,
它们复制出一个他 你都没想过吗
they copied him, and you didn't even think?
现在你还要让它融化 -融化?
Now you're just gonna let him melt. - Melt?!
不 不 不 不
Aw, no, no, no, no!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
追踪那个信号 它越来越弱了
Following the signal. It's fading!
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
就快到了 就快到了
Almost there, almost there...
好了
Here we go!
你不能出去 外面太危险了
You can't go out there. It's not safe!
信号跟丢了 就差一点点
I lost the signal. I got so close.
我们动了 它会飞吗
We've moved. Does it fly?
它从那里消失 然后出现在这里
It disappears there and reappears here.
你不会明白的
You woulndn't understand.
可要是我们已经…转移了
But if we're... somewhere else,
那个没脑袋的家伙可还在外面四处游荡呢
what about that headless thing's still on the loose.
它已经和脑袋一起融化了
Melted with the head.
你能消停一会儿吗
Are you gonna witter on all night?
我得告诉他妈妈
I'll have to tell his mother.
米奇 我必须告诉他妈妈他死了
Mickey. I'll have to tell his mother he's dead,
你又一次把他忘了
and you just went and forgot him. Again!
你说得没错 你是外星人
You were right. You are alien.
就算我忘记了一个叫米奇的小孩
If I did forget some kid called Mickey.
他不是小孩
He's not a kid!
那也是因为我忙着拯救
It's because I'm trying to save every stupid ape
这个星球上的其他蠢货 好吗
blundering about on this planet, all right?
你觉得呢 -没错 挺好的
All right?! - Yes, it is!
你要真是外星人 那你怎么会有北方口音
If you are an alien, why do you sound like you're from the north?
很多星球都有北方啊
Lots of planets have a north!
这个警用电话亭是什么
What's a police public call box?
20世纪50年代的电话亭 这是她的伪装
It's a telephone box, from the 1950s. It's a disguise.
好吧 还有这个塑料人
Ok. And, this, this living plastic,
为什么要攻击我们
what's it got against us?
没为什么 它喜欢你们
Nothing. It loves you.
你们这个星球多好 那么多的烟尘和石油气
You've got a good planet, lots of smoke and oil,
空气里还有各种毒素和尾气 太完美了
plenty of toxins and dioxins in the air, perfect.
奈斯廷意识体正需要这些
Just what the Nestene Consciousness needs.
它的食物储备在战争中被摧毁了
Its food stock was destroyed in the war,
他们的蛋白质行星都腐坏了
its protein planets rotted.
所以地球成了它的晚餐
So. Earth. dinner.
有什么方法阻止它吗
Any way of stopping it?
反塑料剂
Antiplastic.
反塑料剂 -反塑料剂
Antiplastic? - Antiplastic!
不过我要先找到它
But first, I've got to find it.
你们这么小的城市是怎么藏下那个大家伙的
How can you hide something that big in a city this small?
藏什么 -发射器
Hide what? - A transmitter.
意识体靠发射器发射的信号
The Consciousness is controlling all plastic,
控制着所有的塑料
a transmitter boosts the signal.
它长什么样
What does it look like?
就是发射器的样子 又圆又大
Like a transmitter, round and massive,
就在伦敦市中心的附近
somewhere slight bind in the middle of London.
一个巨大的金属的圆形物体
A huge, metal, circular structure,
像碟子和轮胎之类的
like a dish, like a wheel, radial,
就在我们附近
close to where we're standing,
肯定是隐形了
it must be completely invisible.
怎么了
What?
到底怎么了呀
What is it? What?
妙极了
Fantastic!
想象一下 全世界的塑料制品
Think of it. Plastic. all over the world,
每件人造物品都在等待苏醒
every artificial thing waiting to come alive.
橱窗假人 电话 电线 电缆
The shop window dummies, the phones, the wires, the cables.
还有丰胸硅胶
The breast implants.
好在我们找到发射器了
Still, we've found the transmitter.
意识体一定藏在这地下的某处
The Consciousness must be somewhere underneath.
会不会藏在那下面
What about down here?
我觉得很有可能
Looks good to me.
奈斯廷意识体
The Nestene Consciousness.
就在大桶里 一种塑料生物
That's it, inside the vat, a living plastic creature.
赶快把你的反塑料剂倒进去 然后走人
Well then, tip in your Antiplastic and let's go.
我不是来消灭它的
I'm not here to kill it.
得给它一个机会
I've gotta give it a chance!
以《和平条约》为前提求见
I seek audience with the Nestene Consciousness
奈斯廷意识体
under Peaceful Contract.
遵照《影子宣言》第15条公约
According to Convention 15 of the Shadow Proclamation.
谢谢 请问是否可以继续靠近
Thank you. If I might have permission to approach.
天呐
Oh, my God.
米奇 是我 没事了
Mickey! It's me! It's ok!
没事了 -那下面的怪物…
It's all right. - That thing, down there...
洛斯 那坨液体会说话 -你好臭
The liquid, Rose, it can talk! - Oh, you're stinking!
博士 他们没杀他
Doctor, they kept him alive!
总是会有这种可能性的
Yeah, that was always a possibility--
留着他以便之后制作复制品
keep him alive to maintain the copy.
你知道这事却没告诉我
You knew that and never said?!
现在没空唠家常了 谢谢配合
Can we keep domestics outside? Thank you.
请问您是意识体吗
Am I addressing the Consciousness?
谢谢 在我看来
Thank you. if I might observe,
你是通过不正当的技术手段
you infiltrated this civilisation
渗入进这个世界的文明内的
by means of warp, shunt technology.
我带着对您的极大敬意
So, may I suggest, with greatest respect,
建议您放弃
that you shunt off.
少来这套 您这是显而易见的入侵行为
Oh, don't give me that! It's an invasion, plain and simple.
怎么扯到宪法权利上了
Don't talk about Constitutional Rights.
我在和你说话呢
I am talking!
这个星球才刚起步发展
This planet is just starting.
这些愚蠢渺小的人类才刚学会走路
These stupid, little people have only just learnt how to walk.
他们能做到的还有很多很多
They are capable of so much more.
我代表他们请求您
I'm asking you, on their behalf.
离开这里吧 -博士
Please, just go. - Doctor!
那只是以防万一 我并没有打算用的
That was just insurance! I wasn't gonna use it.
我不是来袭击你的 我是来帮你的
I was not attacking you. I'm here to help.
我不是你的敌人 我发誓我真的不是
I'm not you enemy. I swear, I'm not.
你在说什么
What do you mean?
不不 真的不是
No! No! Honestly, no...
没错 这是我的飞船
Yes, that's my ship.
不是这样的
That's not true!
我当然知道 当时我也在
I should know, I was there.
我也参与了那场战争 那不是我的错
I fought in the war. It wasn't my fault.
我救不了你们星球 我一个都救不了
I couldn't save your world. I couldn't save any of them.
它怎么了 -是塔迪斯
What's it doing? - It's the TARDIS.
奈斯廷把它当作某种高端科技 被吓到了
The Nestene's identified it as superior technology, terrified.
它要进入终极形态了
It's going to the final base.
它要开始入侵了
It's starting the invasion...
快走 洛斯 赶快跑啊
Get out, Rose! Just leg it now!
妈 -是你啊 我刚想打电话给你
Mum? - Oh, there you are. I was just gonna phone.
你能领到赔偿金了 我早说过吧
You can get compensation. I've said so.
我刚从警察局拿了份文件 不用谢我
I've got this document thing off the police, don't thank me.
妈 你现在在哪呢 -我在市里
Where are you, mum? - I'm in town.
快走 现在立刻回家
Look, just go! Just go home right now.
宝贝你那边信号不好
Darling, you're breaking up.
我就只是再去买点东西
Listen, I'm just gonna do a bit night shopping.
晚点见
I'll see you later.
妈 妈
Mum? Mum?
是激活信号 传送开始了
It's the activation signal! It's transmitting.
这是世界末日
It's the end of the world.
如果完全不按实际需要消费
There's no point in a spreadsheet if you gonna
那要理财计划有什么用
spend summer money in winter mood.
天呐 我还以为他们是假人呢
Oh my God! I thought they were dummies!
差点吓出了心脏病
I nearly had a heart attack!
是真的 我看的那些故事都是真的
It's true. Everything I've read, all the stories talked true.
快跑 洛斯 赶快跑啊
Get out, Rose! Just get out!
快跑啊 -楼梯塌了
Run! - The stairs have gone.
我没有钥匙
I never got a key...
我们就要死在这了
We're gonna die!
不要啊
No!
时间领主
Time Lord.
别管他了
Just leave him!
你帮不上忙
There's nothing you can do!
我高中学历
I've got no A-Levels.
没有工作
No job.
没有未来
No future.
但我来告诉你我有什么
But I'll tell you what I have got.
杰里科街道小学七岁体操比赛
Jericho Street Junior School Under-7s Gymnastic Team.
我得了铜牌
I got the Bronze!
洛斯
Rose!
现在我们有麻烦了
Now we're in trouble!
洛斯 洛斯 千万别出家门
Rose, Rose, don't go out of the house!
外面不安全 到处是怪物
It's not safe. There are all these things,
他们还会开枪 还会…
and they were shooting, and they were...
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
你真够没用的
That's a lot of good you were!
奈斯廷意识体 轻松搞定
Nestene Consciousness? Easy!
你刚可真没用啊 要不是我你早就死了
You were useless in there! You'd be dead if it wasn't for me.
是啊 多谢相救
Yes, I would. Thank you.
好了 那我走了
Right, then! I'll be off.
除非… 我不知道
Unless... I dunno.
你可以和我一起走
You could come with me.
你要知道 这电话亭可不只在伦敦蹦跶
This box isn't just a London hopper, you know.
它能带你环游宇宙 而且还免费
It goes anywhere in the universe, spare charge.
别去 他是外星人 不是人类
Don't! He's an alien, he's a thing.
他不准跟着来
He's not invited.
你怎么想
What do you think?
你可以…留在这
You could... stay here.
每天就上班吃饭睡觉
Fill your life with work and food and sleep,
你也可以…去任何地方
or you could go uh... anywhere.
总是会像刚才那么危险吗 -是的
Is it always this dangerous? - Yeah.
我去不了
Yeah... I can't.
我得去找我妈
I... I've got to go and find my mum
也总得有人照顾这个大笨蛋
and someone's got to look after this stupid man, so...
好吧 有缘再见
OK. See you around.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
走吧
Come on.
对了 我有提到它还能穿越时间吗
By the way, did I mention it also travels in time?
谢谢 -谢我什么
Thanks. - Thanks for what?
没错
Exactly.
下集预告
现在是公元五十亿年
This is the year five billion,
而就在今天 等一下
and this is the day... hold on...
欢迎来到世界末日
Welcome to the end of the world.
你们是什么人
Who the hell are you?
我是博士 这是洛斯·泰勒
I'm the Doctor, this is Rose Tyler.
她是我的同伴 没问题了吧
She's my plus one, is that all right?
气林族代表
Representing the Forest of Cheam,
有请树人们 宝虹星的默克斯
we have Trees, the Moxx of Balhoon.
伯依之脸 最后一位人类
The Face of Boe, the last human,
卡桑德拉·奥布莱恩女士
the Lady Cassandra O'Brien.
别这么看人家嘛 看我现在多苗条
Oh no, don't stare! Look how thin I am!
不应该发生这种震荡的
That's not supposed to happen.